UNDERCOVER MISS HONG
언더커버 미스홍
I knew it was you.
나는 그것이 당신이라는 것을 알았습니다.
Yehppee was able to keep his face hidden,
예피는 얼굴을 숨길 수 있었고,
but he gave away something else.
하지만 그는 다른 것을 포기했습니다.
What?
무엇?
You already know, Yehppee.
넌 이미 알고 있잖아, 예피.
Hong Keum-bo.
홍금보.
I set a small trap before I sent that email.
작은 함정을 설치했어요 내가 그 이메일을 보내기 전에.
GENERAL MANAGER SO GYEONG-DONG
소경동 과장
I deliberately broke Yehppee Candidate So Gyeong-dong's "D" key,
일부러 Yehppee Candidate를 깨뜨렸어요 소경동의 "D"키,
and as for Yehppee Candidate Cha Jung-il, I broke his "E" key.
Yehppee 차정일 후보는 내가 그 사람의 "E" 키를 부러뜨렸어요.
It's working fine.
잘 작동합니다.
This needs your signature.
여기에는 귀하의 서명이 필요합니다.
No, "E" is the issue.
아니요, "E"가 문제입니다.
The "E" key isn't working.
"E" 키가 작동하지 않습니다.
-Maybe you're pressing it too hard? -Hello.
- 너무 세게 누르는 건 아닐까? -안녕하세요.
Test it out yourself. Why isn't it working?
직접 테스트해보세요. 왜 작동하지 않나요?
-What's wrong… -Mr. Lee.
- 무슨 일이야… - 씨. 이씨.
-Oh, hello. -Help me with this.
-아, 안녕하세요. - 도와주세요.
That keyboard's been acting up all morning.
그 키보드는 아침 내내 행동했어.
The "C" and "E" keys keep switching to English.
"C" 및 "E" 키 계속 영어로 바꾸세요.
Mine's been doing that too.
나도 그런 일을 해왔습니다.
-Let him fix mine first. -Sure, I can wait.
- 그 사람이 내 것을 먼저 고치게 해주세요. -물론이죠. 기다릴 수 있어요.
And the reply email
그리고 답메일은
I received from Yehppee looked like this.
Yehppee에서 받은 내용은 다음과 같습니다.
MEET ME AT 9 O'CLOCK TONIGHT
오늘 밤 9시에 만나요
AT THE SAME PLACE YOU USED TO MEET WITH PRESIDENT KANG
같은 장소에서 강 대표님을 만나셨던 적이 있으신가요?
What's the issue? Everything looks right.
무엇이 문제인가요? 모든 것이 올바르게 보입니다.
It's missing periods.
마침표가 없습니다.
The moment I saw that there were missing periods,
본 순간 누락된 기간이 있었다는 사실,
I knew Bang Jin-mok was Yehppee.
저는 방진목이 예피인줄 알았습니다.
HELLO, YEHPPEE. THIS IS HONG KEUM-BO…
안녕하세요, 예피입니다. 홍금보입니다...
REPLY
답장
Meet me at nine o'clock tonight,
오늘 밤 아홉시에 만나요
at the same place you used to meet with President Kang.
같은 장소에서 강 회장님을 만나본 적이 있잖아요.
Oh no. It doesn't work.
안 돼. 작동하지 않습니다.
Mr. Bang, is your keyboard broken too?
방씨 키보드도 고장났나요?
Forget it.
잊어버리세요.
You can blame your snacks for that.
당신은 간식을 비난할 수 있습니다.
-Right. -Makes sense.
-오른쪽. - 말이 되네요.
I'd like to request a one-on-one meeting,
일대일 미팅을 요청하고 싶습니다.
Mr. Bang Jin-mok.
방진목 선생님.
If you're Hong Keum-bo,
당신이 홍금보라면,
then who's Hong Jang-mi?
그럼 홍장미는 누구야?
She's my younger sister.
그 사람은 내 여동생이에요.
Your sis…
네 여동생은…
You stole your sister's identity to get the job?
넌 네 여동생의 신분을 훔쳤어 일자리를 얻으려면?
It's because of you.
그것은 당신 때문입니다.
You, Yehppee,
너, 예피,
ignored all my emails and vanished, so I came to find you.
내 이메일을 모두 무시하고 사라졌어요 그래서 당신을 찾으러 왔습니다.
Tell me what happened to you.
당신에게 무슨 일이 일어났는지 말해주세요.
If I find no justification for your actions,
내가 정당성을 찾지 못한다면 당신의 행동에 대해,
you can't go home.
당신은 집에 갈 수 없습니다.
You're crazy.
당신은 미쳤어요.
Damn it. Come on.
젠장. 어서 해봐요.
Is there actually a slush fund?
실제로 비자금이 존재하는 걸까요?
Even if there is one…
하나라도 있다고 해도…
we must make it not exist.
우리는 그것이 존재하지 않도록 만들어야 합니다.
Welcome.
환영.
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
You have time to grab a drink and unwind?
음료를 마시며 긴장을 풀 시간이 있나요?
What about the assignment I gave you?
내가 당신에게 준 임무는 어떻습니까?
You should be busy.
당신은 바빠야합니다.
You really work people ragged.
당신은 정말 일하는 사람들이 비정형입니다.
Like father, like son.
아버지처럼, 아들처럼.
You picked up all your daddy's bad habits.
너는 아빠의 나쁜 습관을 모두 흡수했다.
Here's to you milking everyone as always.
언제나처럼 모두의 착유를 위해 여기 있습니다.
I can hear you, you know.
나는 당신의 말을들을 수 있습니다.
I meant for you to hear it.
나는 당신이 그것을 듣도록 의도했습니다.
I'm done dealing with the ethical sludge from the gutter,
난 거래 끝났어 배수구에서 나오는 윤리적 슬러지와 함께,
so find yourself a new moneywasher, sir.
그러니 새로운 돈세탁자를 찾으세요, 선생님.
Hey.
여기요.
Be respectful or don't, but at least commit to one.
존중을 하든 안 하든 하지만 적어도 하나는 약속해야 합니다.
Find yourself a new errand boy, all right?
새로운 심부름꾼을 찾아보세요. 알겠죠?
Asshole.
항문.
I will reject every resignation you file.
나는 당신이 제출하는 모든 사직서를 거부할 것입니다.
The slush fund records and the books the chairman had you cook…
비자금 기록 그리고 회장님이 요리하라고 하신 책들...
You still have them, right?
아직도 가지고 계시죠?
I guess you're at least worried.
적어도 걱정은 하고 계실 것 같아요.
Are you worried I'll take them and run, or leak them to the press?
내가 그걸 가지고 도망갈까봐 걱정되시나요? 아니면 언론에 유출시키나요?
Get every last bit together and hand them over to me.
마지막 부분까지 모두 모아보세요 그리고 그것들을 나에게 넘겨주세요.
I will…
나는…
expose it all for the prosecutors' investigation.
다 공개해라 검찰 수사를 위해.
So I'm saying if you're dead-set on leaving,
그래서 내가 말하는 건 떠날 준비가 되어 있다면,
do some work to benefit your peers before you go.
일 좀 해라 떠나기 전에 동료들에게 도움이 되도록 하세요.
You lazy bum.
게으른 놈아.
Did it ever
그런 적이 있었나요?
occur to you that I might refuse?
내가 거절할 수도 있다는 생각이 드시나요?
No.
아니요.
You're not some foolish coward
당신은 어리석은 겁쟁이가 아니군요
who would throw away such a perfect opportunity.
누가 버릴까 정말 완벽한 기회다.
Drink on the count of three.
3을 세면서 마셔라.
One, two, three.
하나 둘 셋.
Capital Market Investigation Division at the FSS,
자본시장조사과 FSS에서,
Inspector Hong Keum-bo.
홍금보 경감.
Let's reach out to her.
그녀에게 연락해보자.
What if she doesn't bite?
그녀가 물지 않으면 어떻게 되나요?
Why wouldn't she?
그녀는 왜 그러지 않겠습니까?
According to Oh Deok-gyu's mole,
오덕규의 점에 따르면,
Inspector Hong was the one
홍 경감이 그랬다.
who initiated the internal probe into Hanmin's slush fund.
내부 조사를 시작한 사람 한민 비자금에 들어가다.
However, the prosecution asked her to bring back solid evidence first.
그러나 검찰은 그녀에게 물었다. 먼저 확실한 증거를 가져오세요.
So she too is fighting a lonely battle.
그래서 그녀도 외로운 싸움을 하고 있다.
TIP: REGARDING HANMIN'S SLUSH FUND
TIP: 한민 비자금 관련
YOUR MAIL HAS BEEN SENT
귀하의 메일이 전송되었습니다
NEW MAIL FROM HONG KEUM-BO
홍금보가 보낸 새 메일
Let's talk in person.
직접 얘기해보자.
Mr. Kang.
강 선생님.
She took the bait.
그녀는 미끼를 잡았습니다.
Yes, she wants to meet in person.
네, 그 사람은 직접 만나고 싶어해요.
If, by any chance, things go awry,
혹시라도 일이 잘못되면,
say, if I die in an accident--
예를 들어, 내가 사고로 죽는다면...
Look at you obnoxiously jinxing us.
당신이 우리에게 불쾌하게 징징거리는 것을 보세요.
The chairman just might suspect you, so we should be prepared.
회장님이 의심하실 수도 있겠지만 그래서 우리는 준비해야 합니다.
Take a few snapshots of me meeting
회의 중 스냅샷을 몇 장 찍으세요.
with Inspector Hong.
홍 검사님과 함께.
Let's just focus on completing the task at hand.
그냥 집중하자 당면한 작업을 완료하는 중입니다.
A little insurance policy wouldn't hurt.
약간의 보험 정책은 아프지 않을 것입니다.
Life insurance, that is.
생명보험, 즉.
You can pick up the slush fund ledger
비자금 원장을 수령하실 수 있습니다.
at the president's office on the 12th floor
대통령 집무실에서 12층에
in Hanmin's head office.
한민 본사에서
It's being delivered as we speak.
우리가 말하는 대로 전달되고 있습니다.
The deceased victim
사망한 피해자
in the traffic accident that occurred at 6 a.m. today in Mapo-gu
발생한 교통사고에 오늘 오전 6시 마포구
was identified as Hanmin President Kang Myeong-hwi,
으로 확인되었다 한민 강명휘 사장,
who was under investigation for fiduciary breach and embezzlement.
누가 조사를 받았나 신탁 위반 및 횡령의 경우.
What in the world is going on?
도대체 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
Further investigation has revealed
추가 조사 결과 밝혀져
that Hanmin President Kang Myeong-hwi was in the driver's seat.
한민그룹 강명휘 회장 운전석에 있었어요.
The police suspect
경찰은 용의자
he was on his way to work when fatigue led to drowsy driving.
그 사람은 출근 중이었어 피로가 졸음운전으로 이어졌을 때.
The cause of death is currently under investigation.
사망 원인은 현재 조사 중입니다.
The slush fund ledger
비자금 장부
never made its way to the FSS.
FSS에 들어간 적이 없습니다.
It was intercepted before the search and seizure.
차단됐어요 수색 및 압수 직전.
Intercepted? Then where did it go?
가로채셨나요? 그럼 어디로 갔나요?
Well…
음…
Should I tell him Bok-hee took it?
복희가 가져갔다고 해야 하나?
How can I tell him it was incinerated?
그것이 소각되었다는 것을 어떻게 그 사람에게 알릴 수 있나요?
Mr. Bang.
방씨.
You have a copy of the slush fund ledger, don't you?
사본이 있습니다. 비자금 장부에 기록되어 있지 않나요?
No.
아니요.
President Kang Myeong-hwi made it very clear
강명휘 회장 아주 명확하게 해줬어
that if something happened to him, all files were to be destroyed.
만약 그에게 무슨 일이 생기면, 모든 파일이 파괴되었습니다.
So before I met with Executive Director Oh,
그래서 만나기 전에 전무이사 오,
I deleted the backup and shredded everything else.
백업을 삭제했어요 그리고 그 밖의 모든 것을 파쇄했습니다.
You expect me to believe that?
내가 그 말을 믿을 거라고 기대하시나요?
How exactly am I supposed to trust you?
내가 당신을 정확히 어떻게 믿어야 합니까?
It's not like you'll take responsibility for my life.
그렇지 않아요 당신은 내 인생을 책임질 것입니다.
I have a family to support, yet you want me to gamble my life?
부양해야 할 가족이 있고, 그런데 당신은 내가 내 인생을 도박하기를 바라나요?
I understand the sense of fear and helplessness you're feeling right now.
두려운 마음 이해해요 그리고 당신이 지금 느끼고 있는 무력감.
Nine years ago,
9년 전,
whistleblowing cost me my first job.
내부 고발로 인해 첫 직장을 잃었습니다.
She reported Hanmin for accounting fraud,
한민을 분식회계 혐의로 신고했고,
but their countersuit ruined her.
그러나 그들의 반소는 그녀를 망쳤다.
How naive.
얼마나 순진한가.
Wait, my wallet.
잠깐만, 내 지갑.
You can't go back.
당신은 돌아갈 수 없습니다.
I said you can't!
나는 당신이 할 수 없다고 말했다!
The hardest part back then…
그때 가장 힘들었던 게…
wasn't losing my job but losing the people,
직장을 잃은 게 아니었어 하지만 사람을 잃고,
and the regret that I ended up alone.
그리고 결국 혼자가 된 것에 대한 후회도요.
That's why I infiltrated Hanmin to find Yehppee.
그래서 한민에게 잠입한 거야 예피를 찾으러.
Because I know what that feels like.
왜냐하면 나는 그것이 어떤 느낌인지 알기 때문이다.
Mr. Bang.
방씨.
Could you maybe think of this
아마도 이렇게 생각할 수 있을까요?
not as a gamble but as a final investment in me?
도박이 아니라 하지만 나에 대한 최종 투자로?
I'll take responsibility and protect you, no matter what happens.
내가 책임지고 지켜줄게. 무슨 일이 있어도.
I came here…
나는 여기에 왔다…
today…
오늘…
to turn you down.
당신을 거절하기 위해.
Do you really think President Kang's accident…
정말 그렇게 생각하시나요? 강회장 사고…
was a coincidence?
우연이었나요?
EPISODE 8: MONEY MONSTER
에피소드 8: 돈 괴물
ULLALA CHICKEN
울랄라치킨
Hong Jang-mi.
홍장미.
I'll expose you as the scheming brat you are
당신을 폭로하겠습니다 너는 책략을 꾸미는 놈이야
for all to see, even if it kills me.
비록 그것이 나를 죽이더라도 모두가 볼 수 있도록.
Hello there. Welcome to Ullala Chicken.
안녕. 울랄라치킨에 오신 것을 환영합니다.
Sit wherever you'd like.
원하는 곳에 앉으세요.
The menu's there.
메뉴가 거기 있어요.
Are you here by yourself?
여기 혼자 오셨나요?
Yes.
예.
Take your time and let me know when you're ready to order.
시간을 갖고 알려주세요. 주문할 준비가 되면
Are you
당신은
Jang-mi's father, by any chance?
혹시 장미아빠?
You know my Jang-mi?
우리 장미이를 아시나요?
Of course.
물론.
We're alums.
우리는 졸업생입니다.
I thought the name of this place sounded familiar.
여기 이름이 생각났는데 익숙한 것 같았어요.
I guess I was right.
내가 옳았던 것 같아요.
Gosh.
이런.
You must be her senior alum then.
그럼 당신이 그 사람 선배겠군요.
I must show you the warmest hospitality. Just a moment.
나는 당신에게 가장 따뜻한 환대를 보여 주어야합니다. 잠시만요.
Miss?
놓치다?
Miss, are you all right?
아가씨, 괜찮으세요?
Have some water.
물 좀 드세요.
Here.
여기.
Who's that in the photo?
사진 속 저 사람은 누구죠?
That woman underneath the talisman.
부적 밑에 있는 그 여자.
What?
무엇?
That's my eldest daughter.
그 사람은 내 큰 딸이에요.
Honey, she's Jang-mi's senior alum.
여보 장미 선배예요.
Hong Jang-mi is our youngest,
홍장미는 우리 막내이고,
and Hong Keum-bo is our eldest.
그리고 홍금보는 우리의 맏형이에요.
They look alike, right?
비슷해 보이는데요, 그렇죠?
I guess our Jang-mi kept quiet about her sister.
아무래도 우리 장미가 그녀의 여동생에 대해서는 조용히 지냈다.
I guess there's not much to brag about,
자랑할 게 별로 없을 것 같은데,
since she graduated from Seoun University.
서대학교를 졸업한 이후로요.
Seoun University?
서운대학교?
Yeah, it's nothing special. She's an accountant.
응, 특별한 건 아니야. 그녀는 회계사입니다.
She works in Yeouido now, at the Financial Supervisory Service.
지금은 여의도에서 일하고 계시고, 금융감독원에서.
I see.
알겠어요.
Ms. Hong Keum-bo must have quite a brilliant mind.
홍금보 선생님은 꼭 정말 훌륭한 마음이군요.
An educated
교육받은
woman.
여자.
What's that smell?
그 냄새는 무엇입니까?
Oh no, the chicken's burning.
아냐, 닭이 불타고 있어.
-Oh, the chicken. -Honey, go!
-아, 치킨. -여보, 가세요!
This is so good.
정말 좋아요.
It's so tasty.
너무 맛있어요.
Is it?
그렇습니까?
-Eat up, Bom. -Okay.
- 밥 먹어라, 봄. -좋아요.
-You should have some too. -I'm fine.
- 너도 좀 먹어봐야지. -잘 지내요.
Should we save a drumstick for Jang-mi?
장미를 위해 북채를 아껴야 할까요?
You eat it.
당신은 그것을 먹는다.
I'm sure she had her fill growing up.
나는 그녀가 자라면서 만족감을 느꼈을 것이라고 확신합니다.
I'm back.
나는 돌아왔다.
Jang-mi, come and have some fried chicken. Queen Bee bought it.
장미야, 와서 치킨 좀 먹어라. 여왕벌이 샀어요.
I'm fine. Enjoy.
잘 지내요. 즐기다.
ULLALA CHICKEN
울랄라치킨
Auntie Jang-mi has a scratch on her neck.
장미이모 목에 긁힌 상처가 있어요.
-Oh no. -Are you okay?
-안 돼. -괜찮으세요?
Hey.
여기요.
I'm fine. It's nothing.
잘 지내요. 그것은 아무것도 아니다.
She just has so many secrets.
그녀는 비밀이 너무 많습니다.
It appears that our clever kiddo
우리 영리한 아이인 것 같아요
had us completely fooled.
우리를 완전히 속였습니다.
Seriously, a 35-year-old impersonating a 20-year-old?
솔직히 35세 20대 사칭?
Go Bok-hee, how old are you?
고복희 씨, 몇 살이에요?
I'm 29.
나는 29살이다.
Exactly.
정확합니다.
So I'm six whole years older than you.
그러니까 나는 당신보다 6살이나 더 많아요.
When you were a snot-nosed kid about to enter school,
네가 코딱지 꼬마였을 때 곧 학교에 입학할 예정이고,
I was eating jajangmyeon with my elementary school diploma in hand.
짜장면을 먹고 있었어요 초등학교 졸업장을 손에 들고.
And what if I tell everyone outside--
그리고 밖에 있는 사람들에게 말하면 어쩌지...
I'm too tired today.
오늘은 너무 피곤해요.
So if you're going to tell them,
그러니 그들에게 말하려고 한다면,
do it tomorrow, Queen Bee.
내일 하세요, 여왕벌님.
Hey, bro. It's Jin-mok.
안녕, 형제. 진목입니다.
Yeah.
응.
Are there any updates on the experienced-hire role
업데이트가 있나요? 경력 채용 역할에 대해
I submitted my résumé for?
내가 이력서를 제출한 이유는 무엇입니까?
Oh, right.
아, 그렇죠.
The HR manager said he received a call from Hanmin.
인사담당자가 말했다. 한민에게서 전화가 왔다.
They keep passing you over for promotion, leaving you stuck in a dead-end division,
승진을 위해 계속 당신을 놓치고 있어요. 당신을 막다른 골목에 갇히게 하고,
yet they won't even let you quit.
그런데도 그들은 당신이 그만두는 것을 허락하지 않을 것입니다.
Did you get on the higher-ups' bad side or something?
윗사람한테 올라갔어?" 나쁜 면인가?
That's a bonus from the chairman
회장님 상여금이군요
for your hard work on the last project.
지난 프로젝트의 노고에 감사드립니다.
If you'll excuse me.
실례합니다.
NON-DISCLOSURE AGREEMENT
비공개 계약
MANAGER BANG JIN-MOK, TRADING DIVISION
무역사업부 방진목 과장
I'm sorry.
미안해요.
Why would you be sorry?
왜 미안하겠어요?
SEPTEMBER 23, 1988 SIGNATORY: BANG JIN-MOK
1988년 9월 23일 서명자: 방진목
I just did what I was told.
나는 단지 내가 들은 대로 했을 뿐입니다.
Back then, I needed the money
그땐 돈이 필요했지
and thought that was my best option.
그리고 그것이 최선의 선택이라고 생각했습니다.
Then you just need to hang in there.
그렇다면 거기에 매달려 있으면됩니다.
Not getting fired is key if you're stuck.
막히면 해고되지 않는 것이 중요합니다.
This is no time for pride when you have a sick kid.
지금은 자존심을 가질 때가 아니다 아픈 아이가 있을 때.
Right. Sure.
오른쪽. 확신하는.
Let me know if anything changes.
변경사항이 있으면 알려주세요.
I'll talk to you later.
나중에 얘기하겠습니다.
Thanks.
감사해요.
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
Prep the main conference room by 3 p.m. for the emergency branch manager meeting.
오후 3시까지 주 회의실을 준비하세요. 긴급 지점장 회의를 위해.
-Yes, ma'am.
-네, 부인.
Thanks.
감사해요.
Do you remember Hong Keum-bo?
홍금보를 기억하시나요?
She's the one you had me handle last time.
지난번에 당신이 나한테 맡겼던 사람이 그 사람이에요.
There's a car parked by my shop,
내 가게 옆에 차가 주차되어 있는데,
and it's registered under her name.
그리고 그 사람 이름으로 등록되어 있어요.
-Hello, sir. -Hong Keum-bo?
-안녕하세요 선생님. -홍금보요?
The car is parked there, but no one's inside it?
차는 거기 주차되어 있고, 그런데 안에는 아무도 없나요?
You said the spoiled brat who came by recently
버릇없는 놈이라고 했잖아 최근에 누가 왔는지
was the chairman's grandson, right?
회장 손자였죠?
I think the girl who interfered then was Hong Keum-bo.
내 생각엔 그때 방해했던 그 여자가 홍금보였습니다.
So basically,
그래서 기본적으로,
they came separately, but left together in one car.
따로 왔는데, 하지만 한 차에 함께 남겨졌습니다.
How do they know each other?
그들은 서로를 어떻게 아는가?
Start digging again.
다시 발굴을 시작하세요.
You'd better not mess up this time.
이번에는 엉망으로 만들지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
Ms. Song.
송 씨.
If you have a spare moment,
잠시 여유가 있으시면,
can we talk briefly in my office right now?
우리 짧게 얘기 좀 할 수 있을까 지금 내 사무실에 있어?
Yes, sure.
네, 그렇죠.
It sounded like you were on an urgent call.
그것은 다음과 같이 들렸다 너 긴급 통화 중이었어.
I hope I didn't disturb you.
내가 당신을 방해하지 않았기를 바랍니다.
Not at all.
별말씀을요.
It was just another work call.
또 다른 업무 전화였습니다.
A few days ago, one of our female employees
며칠 전, 우리 여자 직원 중 한 명
was attacked by an assailant on company grounds.
가해자에게 공격을 받았습니다 회사 근거로.
Pardon?
뭐라고요?
One of our employees?
우리 직원 중 한 명이요?
Yes, I witnessed the event and handed the attacker over to the police.
네, 그 사건을 목격하고 건네줬어요 공격자는 경찰에 신고했습니다.
He turned out to be Ms. Go's recently released brother.
그는 다음과 같이 밝혀졌습니다. 고씨의 최근 석방된 동생.
He claimed he mistook his victim for Ms. Go.
그는 자신이 실수했다고 주장했다 고씨의 피해자.
I thought I would let you know
너한테 알려줄 거라 생각했는데
since it concerns one of the employees under your care.
직원 중 한 사람에 관한 것이기 때문에 당신의 보살핌 아래 있습니다.
I suggest reinforcing security measures.
보안 조치를 강화할 것을 제안합니다.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
I'll take care of it.
내가 처리할게.
All right then.
그럼요.
Where did he go?
그는 어디로 갔습니까?
FULL-SERVICE SHOE REPAIR
풀 서비스 신발 수리
Did you meet Yehppee?
예피를 만났나요?
Jeez, what are you doing?
이런, 뭐하는 거야?
So who was it?
그럼 누구였나요?
It was Bang Jin-mok.
방진목이었습니다.
I knew it.
나는 그것을 알고 있었다.
See? What did I tell you? I always knew it was him.
보다? 내가 뭐라고 말했지? 나는 항상 그 사람이라는 것을 알고있었습니다.
It's the first time I'm hearing about it.
나는 그것에 대해 처음 듣는다.
So when is he going to hand over the files?
그럼 그 사람은 언제 갈 거야? 파일을 넘겨?
There's nothing to hand over.
넘겨드릴 일이 없습니다.
He said even the backups were destroyed.
백업도 다 파괴됐다고 하더군요.
Man, you're one naive lady.
이봐, 당신은 정말 순진한 여자야.
You believe that? He's just playing it safe.
당신은 그것을 믿나요? 그는 단지 안전하게 플레이하고 있습니다.
You have to butter him up gently.
그에게 부드럽게 버터를 발라주어야 합니다.
Try to gain his trust, like I did with you.
그의 신뢰를 얻으려고 노력하고, 내가 너한테 그랬던 것처럼.
Think about it.
생각해 보세요.
You refused to go undercover at first,
당신은 처음에는 잠복을 거부했지만,
but I never gave up until you were persuaded.
하지만 난 절대 포기하지 않았어 당신이 설득될 때까지.
Only because I was sick of it.
단지 내가 지쳤기 때문이다.
It was done with great care and devotion.
그것은 큰 관심과 헌신으로 이루어졌습니다.
Hong, you also need to try everything you can with him.
홍 너도 해봐야지 그와 함께 할 수 있는 모든 것.
Man.
남성.
The stock market, exchange rates, and bonds nowadays?
주식시장, 환율, 그리고 요즘에는 채권?
Something feels off with all of it.
모든 것이 뭔가 기분이 좋지 않습니다.
It feels like the calm before the storm.
폭풍 전야의 고요함 같은 느낌이다.
At this rate, something major might hit the country.
이 속도로, 뭔가 큰 일이 나라에 타격을 줄 수도 있습니다.
We might need to rush a little.
조금 서둘러야 할 수도 있습니다.
Oh right.
아 맞다.
He's not here, right? Polish these for me quickly.
그 사람은 여기 없어요, 그렇죠? 빨리 다듬어 주세요.
These came from Mr. Yun at General Affairs, right?
이건 윤씨에게서 온 거예요 총무부에서요?
-The heels need to be replaced. -Don't be ridiculous. Hurry.
- 힐을 교체해야 합니다. -웃기는 소리 하지 마세요. 서두르다.
But they're all worn out.
그런데 다들 지쳤어요.
Hand it over!
넘겨주세요!
Do I owe you something?
내가 당신에게 빚진 게 있나요?
I have nothing. It was all destroyed.
나는 아무것도 없다. 모두 파괴되었습니다.
That's how I managed to survive that infiltrator manhunt last time.
그게 내가 살아남을 수 있었던 방법이야 저번에 그 침입자 수색이요.
You only survived because you handed over my photos.
너만 살아남았어 당신이 내 사진을 넘겨줬으니까요.
I handed over photos last time,
지난번에 사진을 넘겨줬는데,
but this time, I could hand over the real Hong Keum-bo.
하지만 이번엔 넘겨줄 수 있었어 진짜 홍금보.
Is this Admin? Is the chairman in?
이 사람이 관리자인가요? 회장님 계시나요?
Are you crazy?
제정신이에요?
If I really wanted to, I'm sure I could land
내가 정말로 원했다면, 난 분명 착륙할 수 있을 거라고 확신해
a private meeting with the chairman to discuss your past actions.
회장과의 비공개 회의 당신의 과거 행동에 대해 논의하기 위해.
Oh, so you've resorted to blackmail now?
아, 그럼 이제 협박까지 했다는 겁니까?
You started it.
당신이 시작했어요.
Give me that. Go away.
그거 주세요. 저리 가요.
-Mr. Bang! -Go away!
-씨. 쾅! -저리 가요!
ULLALA CHICKEN
울랄라치킨
It's already 9 p.m., but we haven't had a single customer.
벌써 저녁 9시가 되었는데, 하지만 우리는 단 한 명의 고객도 없었습니다.
Sales have been down by half since last month,
매출이 절반으로 줄었어요 지난달부터,
and we might not be able to afford rent at this rate.
그리고 우리는 그러지 못할 수도 있어요 이 가격으로 임대료를 감당하세요.
We're in the red if we factor in labor costs.
우리는 빨간색입니다 인건비까지 고려한다면.
Maybe we should ask Keum-bo for help?
금보에게 도움을 요청해야 하지 않을까요?
Honey. Seriously?
꿀. 진지하게?
You want to borrow money from your unmarried daughter?
돈을 빌리고 싶나요? 미혼 딸에게서요?
I was just thinking out loud.
나는 단지 큰 소리로 생각하고있었습니다.
Why are you getting angry? Jeez.
왜 화를 내나요? 이런.
We should just start a farm in our hometown--
우리는 단지 우리 고향에서 농장을 시작하세요--
You think anyone can farm?
누구나 농사를 지을 수 있다고 생각하시나요?
You can't live off dirt!
흙으로만 살 수는 없어!
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
Take this too.
이것도 가져가세요.
Goodness.
선량.
She used to be so gentle when she was young.
그녀는 원래 너무 온화했지 그녀가 어렸을 때.
When did she become such a brute?
그녀는 언제 그렇게 짐승이 되었습니까?
NEW KOREA FUND THE FIRST-RATE FUND!
뉴코리아펀드 일류 펀드!
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
"New Korea Fund"?
'뉴코리아펀드'?
New Korea Fund…
뉴코리아펀드…
GET RICH IN THE NEW MILLENNIUM! NEW KOREA FUND
새천년에 부자가 되세요! 뉴코리아펀드
The stock market plunged a record 38 points today…
주식시장이 폭락했다 오늘 38점 기록…
Interest rates are at a two-year high…
금리 2년만에 최고…
Stock prices have dropped to their lowest in five years…
주가는 하락했다 5년 만에 최저치…
The IMF Managing Director maintained that Korea's financial markets
IMF 총재는 유지했다. 한국의 금융시장은
are not facing a crisis like those in Southeast Asia.
위기에 처해 있지 않다 동남아시아의 사람들처럼요.
But Korea's stock market has frozen over,
하지만 한국 증시는 얼어붙었고,
with foreign investors beginning to sell off their shares.
외국인 투자자들과 주식을 팔기 시작합니다.
We're both busy people, so we can skip the pleasantries.
우리 둘 다 바쁜 사람들이잖아요. 그래서 우리는 즐거운 시간을 건너뛸 수 있습니다.
I'm calling out of concern for the country, sir.
걱정돼서 전화했어요 나라를 위해서요, 선생님.
Sure.
확신하는.
I look forward to seeing you at a year-end celebration, Vice Minister.
나는 당신을 만나기를 기대합니다 송년회에 차관님.
He assures me everything will be fine.
그는 나에게 모든 것이 잘 될 것이라고 확신합니다.
Even the oil shocks that sent prices soaring
오일쇼크에도 그로 인해 가격이 급등하게 됐어요
and the foreign debt crisis in the '80s
그리고 80년대 외채위기
all came and went, like a passing breeze.
모든 것이 지나가는 산들바람처럼 오고 갔다.
Hanmin managed to endure and stand strong through it all.
한민은 버텼다 그리고 그 모든 것을 이겨내며 굳건히 서십시오.
That's true.
그것은 사실이다.
That reminds me.
그게 생각나네요.
We sure made a lot of money back then.
그때 우리는 확실히 돈을 많이 벌었습니다.
I sense a similar…
비슷한 느낌이 드네요...
No,
아니요,
it'll be even grander this time.
이번에는 더 웅장해질 거예요.
I sense a major opportunity on the horizon.
나는 큰 기회를 느낀다 지평선에.
There's no issue with the slush fund, is there?
문제없어요 비자금으로요?
Is the OW Club fine? And Nora too?
OW클럽은 괜찮은가요? 노라도요?
Most certainly, sir.
가장 확실합니다.
All right.
괜찮은.
You can show Mr. Shin and Mr. Oh in now.
이제 신씨와 오씨를 보여주실 수 있습니다.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
How are the sales
매출은 어때요?
for the New Korea Fund?
신한국기금?
It was launched three weeks ago,
3주 전에 출시됐는데,
but it's underperforming.
하지만 실적이 저조해요.
After a US investment firm
미국 투자회사 이후
put out a report telling investors to leave Asia,
보고서를 내다 투자자들에게 아시아를 떠나라고 말하고,
the 500 mark collapsed immediately.
500 표시는 즉시 붕괴되었습니다.
With investors spooked, sales are struggling.
투자자들이 불안해하는 가운데, 판매가 어려움을 겪고 있습니다.
Increase the sales target.
판매 목표를 높이세요.
Pardon?
뭐라고요?
We need to raise the bar to at least meet the average.
우리는 기준을 높여야 합니다 최소한 평균을 충족하려면.
But…
하지만…
Send out a fax to all the branches,
전 지점에 팩스를 발송하고,
and gather all the branch managers for a training.
지점장들을 다 모아서 훈련을 위해.
Yes, sir. I'll see to it immediately.
네, 선생님. 즉시 처리하겠습니다.
Our branch's performance is on the line, and it's everyone's responsibility.
우리 지점의 성과가 위태로워요. 그리고 그것은 모두의 책임입니다.
Let's put everything into selling the New Korea Fund.
다 넣어보자 신한국펀드 매각에 나섰다.
The head office says it'll take full responsibility.
본사가 말하길 전적으로 책임을 질 것입니다.
See?
보다?
All right now.
이제 됐어요.
Remember to smile.
미소 짓는 것을 잊지 마세요.
Mi-sook.
미숙.
It's too bad they raised the target when you've already sold so much.
그들이 목표를 높인 것은 안타깝습니다. 이미 너무 많이 팔았을 때.
If the branch doesn't meet its quota,
지점이 할당량을 충족하지 못하는 경우,
that reward's off the table, no matter how much you sell.
그 보상은 불가능해요 아무리 많이 팔아도.
I'll just have to try harder then.
그럼 좀 더 노력해야겠습니다.
Hello, sir.
안녕하세요, 선생님.
This is Kim Mi-sook from Hanmin's Magang Branch.
김미숙 입니다 한민 마강지점에서
Hong Jang-mi.
홍장미.
No, Hong Keum-bo.
아니, 홍금보.
You're done for.
당신은 끝났습니다.
I heard your brother was released.
네 동생이 석방됐다고 들었어.
How did you know, ma'am?
어떻게 아셨나요, 부인?
How did I know?
내가 어떻게 알았지?
Your brother attacked one of our female employees
네 형이 공격했어 우리 여자 직원 중 한 명
near our office the other night.
어젯밤 우리 사무실 근처에서.
He mistook her for you.
그는 그녀를 당신으로 착각했습니다.
Auntie Jang-mi has a scratch on her neck.
장미이모 목에 긁힌 상처가 있어요.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
President Shin witnessed it happen and had to go to the police station.
신 회장이 이를 목격했다. 그리고 경찰서에 가야만 했어요.
President Shin did?
신 회장이 그랬나요?
Must I worry about your family affairs?
내가 당신의 가족 문제에 대해 걱정해야 합니까?
Talk to your brother and keep him under control.
형이랑 얘기 좀 해봐 그리고 그를 통제하십시오.
Don't cause trouble.
문제를 일으키지 마십시오.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
죄송해요, 부인.
What did you need to tell me?
나에게 무엇을 말해야 했나요?
I came to let you know Ms. Kang,
강씨에게 소식을 전하러 왔습니다.
the chairman's daughter, is doing well.
회장 딸은 잘 지내요.
Nothing to report on President Shin?
신 회장에 대해서는 보고할 게 없나?
No.
아니요.
All right. You may leave.
알았어. 떠날 수도 있습니다.
Hong Keum-bo?
홍금보?
Start digging again.
다시 발굴을 시작하세요.
You'd better not mess up this time.
이번에는 엉망으로 만들지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
Why you little…
왜 꼬마야...
-Damn it. -Get in there.
-젠장. - 거기 들어가세요.
Come in.
들어오세요.
Sir,
선생님,
I heard you were inconvenienced by my brother recently.
불편하셨다고 들었습니다 최근에 내 동생이.
Please accept my apologies.
제 사과를 받아주세요.
I'm fine.
잘 지내요.
You should be extra careful when you're coming in and leaving work.
각별히 조심해야 해 출근할 때와 퇴근할 때.
By the way,
그건 그렇고,
was the assaulted female employee
폭행당한 여직원이었어
Hong Jang-mi?
홍장미?
Yes, it was Ms. Hong.
네, 홍씨였습니다.
I see.
알겠어요.
DIRECTOR YUN JAE-BEOM FINANCIAL SUPERVISORY SERVICE
Director 윤재범 금융감독 서비스
You've reached Yun Jae-beom.
윤재범 님에게 닿았습니다.
Sir, this is Shin Jung-woo.
선생님, 신정우입니다.
My goodness, President Shin!
맙소사, 신 회장님!
Would you be free for dinner tonight?
오늘 밤에 저녁 식사 시간이 있으신가요?
I am.
그래요.
Even if I wasn't, I'd make time.
아니더라도 시간을 낼 거에요.
Where shall I meet you?
어디서 만날까요?
Try some of this, sir.
이것 좀 드셔보세요, 선생님.
This is for me?
이건 나를 위한 건가요?
My goodness, how kind of you.
맙소사, 당신은 정말 친절해요.
You're giving me this precious hairtail.
이 귀한 갈치를 나에게 주시네요.
Look at my suit matching its scales.
비늘과 어울리는 내 양복을 보세요.
That is so delicious.
정말 맛있어요.
I assume you're planning to have Inspector Hong Keum-bo
계획하고 계신 것 같아요 홍금보 경위님을 모십니다
return to the Seoul office at some point.
어느 시점에 서울 사무실로 돌아가세요.
Yes, of course.
물론이죠.
I can't just leave her suffering down there all alone.
난 그녀를 그냥 떠날 수 없어 거기서 혼자 고통받고 있어요.
She might not be aware of the great dangers that await her.
그 사람은 모를 수도 있지 그녀를 기다리고 있는 엄청난 위험.
Your subordinate's safety should be the priority.
부하직원의 안전 우선순위가 되어야 합니다.
You should take her back immediately.
즉시 그녀를 다시 데려가야 합니다.
I want to bring her back just as much.
나도 그녀를 다시 데려오고 싶다.
However, unlike us, who prioritize safety and well-being,
그러나 우리와는 달리, 안전과 웰빙을 최우선으로 생각하는 사람,
Hong Keum-bo always puts winning above all else.
홍금보님은 항상 무엇보다 승리.
It's all-or-nothing with her.
그녀에게는 전부 아니면 전무입니다.
So unless she's knocked out,
그러니까 그녀가 쓰러지지 않는 한,
she would never back out of her fight.
그녀는 결코 싸움에서 물러나지 않을 것입니다.
I mean, you two
내 말은, 너희 둘은
were…
있었다…
You know?
아시죠?
Come on, as if I need to say it out loud.
어서, 내가 큰 소리로 말해야 할 것처럼.
Could this be any tastier?
이게 더 맛있을 수도 있지 않을까?
The New Korea Fund's returns keep falling,
뉴코리아펀드 수익률이 계속 하락하고 있는데,
but the higher-ups are just riding the branches hard
하지만 고위층은 그냥 가지를 열심히 타고
over their weak sales.
판매 부진 때문이다.
To make matters worse,
설상가상으로,
customers want us to take responsibility because we sold it to them.
고객은 우리가 책임지기를 원합니다. 왜냐하면 우리가 그것을 그들에게 팔았기 때문입니다.
This is just between us,
이건 우리 사이의 일이야
but hasn't the company made enough from the service fees?
하지만 회사가 충분히 벌지 않았나요? 서비스 수수료에서?
Corporate employees like us just do as we're told.
우리같은 회사원들 그냥 우리가 말한 대로 하세요.
How much responsibility do they expect us to take?
얼마나 많은 책임이 있는가? 그들은 우리가 걸릴 것으로 기대합니까?
Could you maybe think of this
아마도 이렇게 생각할 수 있을까요?
not as a gamble but as a final investment in me?
도박이 아니라 하지만 나에 대한 최종 투자로?
I'll take responsibility and protect you, no matter what happens.
내가 책임지고 지켜줄게. 무슨 일이 있어도.
Anyone willing to take responsibility during this hot mess
책임을 지겠다는 의지가 있는 사람 이 뜨거운 혼란 속에서
is either naive…
순진하거나…
or completely insane.
아니면 완전히 미쳤거나.
Or maybe they're just desperately earnest.
아니면 그저 필사적으로 진지한 것일 수도 있습니다.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
It's Bang Jin-mok.
방진목입니다.
Come to the bridge by the Han River where we met last time, right now.
한강 다리로 오세요 지난번에 만났던 곳, 바로 지금.
I know about the 24 billion won that was embezzled by the OW Club.
나는 240억 원에 대해 알고 있다 OW클럽이 횡령한 것입니다.
So,
그래서,
you knew about it going in.
당신은 그것이 들어가는 것을 알고있었습니다.
Just hand over the materials, and we'll take care of the rest.
재료만 건네주고, 나머지는 우리가 처리하겠습니다.
We'll make sure your identity remains secret.
우리는 확실히 할 것입니다 귀하의 신원은 비밀로 유지됩니다.
You can trust me.
당신은 나를 믿을 수 있습니다.
I need a little more time.
시간이 좀 더 필요해요.
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES MAGANG BRANCH
한민투자증권 마강점
NEW KOREA FUND SALES PERFORMANCE
뉴코리아펀드 판매실적
Ms. Kim.
김 씨.
Ms. Kim Mi-sook?
김미숙 선생님?
Yes?
예?
Attention, everyone.
모두들 주목하세요.
Here at the Magang Branch,
여기 마강점에서는
Ms. Kim Mi-sook is the top salesperson.
김미숙씨는 영업사원 1위다.
She's number one.
그녀는 최고의 사람입니다.
Now, let's stop making excuses.
이제 변명은 그만합시다.
Take after Ms. Kim and give it all you've got to sell.
김씨를 닮아라 그리고 당신이 팔 수 있는 모든 것을 그에게 주세요.
Don't just stand there and give her applause.
거기 그냥 서있지 말고 그리고 그녀에게 박수를 보내주세요.
Congratulations.
축하해요.
Well done.
잘하셨어요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Why do you keep coming home so late?
왜 자꾸 집에 늦게 오나요?
Why didn't you tell me you were attacked by Go Bok-cheol?
왜 나한테 말하지 않았어? 고복철한테 습격당했어?
How did you find out?
어떻게 알게 되었나요?
Right. Shin Jung-woo.
오른쪽. 신정우.
What did I tell you about calling the president by his name?
내가 너한테 뭐라고 말했지? 대통령의 이름을 부르는 것에 대해?
Queen Bee,
여왕벌,
you know how old I really am.
내가 진짜 몇 살인지 아시죠?
He and I are in the same age group.
그와 나는 같은 연령층이다.
We're only three years apart.
우리는 3년밖에 차이가 나지 않아요.
We're having a celebration party, so come on out.
축하 파티를 하고 있어요. 그러니 나오세요.
-Okay. -We'll be there soon.
-좋아요. -곧 도착할 거예요.
Let me just get changed first.
나 먼저 갈아입을게.
Quit, leave the country, do whatever you must to stay safe.
그만둬, 나라를 떠나 안전을 유지하기 위해 필요한 모든 조치를 취하십시오.
I hate having to tell the victim to be careful.
피해자에게 말해야 하는 게 싫다 조심하세요.
But I think Go Bok-cheol, that crazy bastard,
그런데 내 생각엔 고복철이, 그 미친놈아,
will end up retaliating.
결국 보복을 당하게 됩니다.
Yeah, he's totally a crazy bastard.
응, 그 사람 완전 미친 놈이네.
I'm going to quit and move out of the dorms soon too.
그만둘 거야 그리고 빨리 기숙사에서 나가라.
Until then…
그때까지는…
can you keep this a secret from our roommates?
이거 비밀로 해줄 수 있어? 우리 룸메이트한테서요?
I'm asking you a favor.
부탁이 있어요.
Since you're asking for a favor, fine.
부탁을 하는 거니까 괜찮습니다.
Let's act natural.
자연스럽게 행동하자.
Sure, Queen Bee.
물론이죠, 여왕벌님.
Mi-sook, congratulations on being the top salesperson.
미숙아, 축하해 최고의 영업사원이 되는 것에 대해.
Congratulations.
축하해요.
Ready?
준비가 된?
-Congratulations. -I was just lucky.
-축하해요. -그냥 운이 좋았던 것 뿐이에요.
No need to be humble.
겸손할 필요는 없습니다.
Fine. I did work really hard.
괜찮은. 정말 열심히 일했어요.
Ta-da!
짜잔!
This is for the sales queen, Mi-sook.
영업왕 미숙님을 위한 글입니다.
And this is for her junior, Bom!
그리고 이건 후배 봄을 위한 것!
How exciting.
정말 신난다.
And…
그리고…
this is for you, Jang-mi.
이건 널 위한 거야, 장미야.
For what?
무엇을 위해?
Next week will be the end of our three-month probationary period.
다음주가 끝이네요 3개월의 수습 기간 중입니다.
And this is for you, Queen Bee.
그리고 이것은 당신을 위한 것입니다, 여왕벌님.
What? Me too?
무엇? 저도요?
Isn't this too much…
이건 너무한거 아닌가...
It's not too much for you.
그것은 당신에게 너무 많은 것이 아닙니다.
Mommy, I'm sleepy.
엄마, 나 졸려요.
It's already past nine.
벌써 9시가 지났네요.
Let's save your donut for tomorrow, okay?
내일을 위해 도넛을 남겨두자, 알았지?
Shall we go to bed?
자러 갈까요?
Let me put her to bed first.
먼저 그녀를 침대에 눕히겠습니다.
Good night, Bom.
잘 자, 봄.
Nighty-night.
밤잠.
Let's eat.
먹자.
Mom told me to move in with Dad once my probationary period's over.
엄마가 아빠랑 같이 들어가라고 했어 수습기간이 끝나면요.
What should I tell my roommates?
룸메이트에게 뭐라고 말해야 하나요?
If I stall, Go Bok-cheol is bound to shake me down again.
내가 꾸물대면 고복철 나를 다시 흔들게 될 것입니다.
In a crappy situation like this, the best move is to run.
이런 난감한 상황에서, 가장 좋은 방법은 달리는 것입니다.
I'll be off to LA, no matter what.
나는 무슨 일이 있어도 LA로 떠날 것이다.
-Where are you going? -Where?
-어디 가세요? -어디?
I just need some fresh air.
단지 신선한 공기가 필요할 뿐입니다.
There she goes again.
그녀는 또 간다.
She works out in the parking lot whenever she's frustrated.
그녀는 주차장에서 운동한다 그녀가 좌절할 때마다.
It's the emergency stairs when she's at work. I saw her.
비상계단이에요 그녀가 직장에 있을 때. 나는 그녀를 보았다.
Let's not get sentimental.
감상적으로 생각하지 맙시다.
If I just get Yehppee on my side, Chairman Kang Pil-beom will be…
Yehppee만 내 편으로 만들어준다면, 강필범 회장은…
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Hey, Hong. We're in big trouble.
안녕, 홍. 우리는 큰 문제에 빠졌습니다.
-What happened? -Turn on the news.
-무슨 일이에요? -뉴스를 켜세요.
What?
무엇?
In an effort to address the mounting foreign exchange crisis,
해결하기 위한 노력의 일환으로 점점 커지는 외환위기,
the government has decided to request a bailout from the IMF.
정부는 요청하기로 결정했습니다 IMF 구제금융.
Leaving behind the title of model economy,
모델경제라는 타이틀을 뒤로하고,
this served as an acknowledgment of a national bankruptcy.
이건 인정의 역할을 했어 국가 파산.
The government is expected to announce this decision
정부는 다음과 같이 예상한다. 이 결정을 발표하다
in a nationwide address tomorrow.
내일 전국 주소로.
During a series of meetings earlier today with the IMF Deputy Managing Director
오늘 오전 일련의 회의에서 IMF 부총재와 함께
and the US Under Secretary of the Treasury, who are visiting Korea,
그리고 미국 차관 한국을 방문하는 재무부 장관님,
the Korean government reportedly agreed that seeking IMF assistance is inevitable.
한국 정부도 이에 동의한 것으로 전해졌다 IMF 지원을 구하는 것은 불가피하다는 것이다.
The bailout request is expected to total about 35 billion dollars,
구제금융 요청은 총계로 예상된다 약 350억 달러,
given that the short-term external debt
단기 대외 부채가 있다는 점을 고려하면
totaling 70 billion dollars is due within a year.
총 700억 달러 1년 안에 납부해야 합니다.
In addition, the government…
아울러 정부는…
Hello?
안녕하세요?
An emergency executive meeting?
긴급 임원회의요?
Yes, I'll call the emergency contacts.
네, 비상연락처에 전화하겠습니다.
Who was that?
그 사람은 누구였나요?
The president has called an emergency meeting
대통령이 전화했어요 긴급 회의
for division heads and above.
부서장 이상의 경우.
Help me make these calls.
전화 걸 수 있게 도와주세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
I'll call everyone up to here.
여기까지 모두 부를게요.
You should start from here.
여기서부터 시작해야 합니다.
-I'll call up to here. -Okay.
- 여기까지 전화할게요. -좋아요.
Hello, I'm calling from Admin.
안녕하세요, 관리자님에게서 전화가 왔습니다.
Mr. Oh, it's Hong Jang-mi.
오 선생님, 홍장미입니다.
I'm calling from Admin.
관리자님에게서 전화가 왔습니다.
-President Shin Jung-woo… -He called an emergency meeting.
-신정우 회장… -그는 긴급 회의를 소집했습니다.
Please head to the office.
사무실로 가주세요.
-I'm calling from Admin. -Hello, this is Hong Jang-mi.
-관리자에게서 전화가 왔습니다. -안녕하세요 홍장미 입니다.
Why won't he pick up?
그 사람은 왜 전화를 안 받나요?
It's fine. Sit.
괜찮습니다. 앉다.
Hey.
여기요.
Did you call the Ministry of Finance and Economy?
전화하셨나요? 재정경제부요?
Yes, there will be a special address tomorrow
네, 그럴 거예요 내일 특별 연설
and term negotiations next week.
그리고 다음 주에 임기 협상이 있을 겁니다.
How much are they borrowing?
그들은 얼마를 빌리고 있나요?
Well…
음…
That I don't…
나는 그렇지 않다…
According to the deputy prime minister's 10 p.m. press conference earlier,
부총리의 말에 따르면 오후 10시 앞서 기자회견,
the government will initially seek
정부는 우선적으로 모색할 것이다.
aid of 20 billion dollars from the US and Japan.
200억 달러 지원 미국과 일본에서.
Twenty billion dollars…
200억 달러…
You make sure to cash every donation check I send,
현금 꼭 챙겨가세요 내가 보내는 모든 기부 수표,
yet you have me find out such crucial intel from the news?
그런데 당신은 내가 알아내게 해주세요 뉴스에서 그렇게 중요한 정보를 얻었나요?
Just last week, when I went to check…
지난주에 확인하러 갔을 때...
Listen to me.
내 말을 들어보세요.
You must think with a father's heart
아버지의 마음으로 생각해야 합니다.
and consider your kid who's studying abroad in the US.
그리고 당신의 아이를 고려해보세요 미국에서 유학중인 사람입니다.
You must consider how much money you'll need for that kid's future.
돈이 얼마인지 생각해봐야지 그 아이의 미래를 위해서는 당신이 필요할 거예요.
I've already done my calculations.
나는 이미 계산을 끝냈습니다.
Let's first arrange
먼저 정리해보자
a meeting today with vice ministers in attendance.
오늘 회의 차관들이 참석한 가운데.
I'll take care of the rest!
나머지는 내가 처리할게!
Do you hear me?
내 말 들리나요?
Damn it.
젠장.
You've reached Hanmin.
한민에 도착했습니다.
Hello, you've reached Hanmin.
안녕하세요 한민에 오셨습니다.
There they are.
거기 있습니다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
This isn't the result of our mismanagement or incompetence.
이건 결과가 아니야 우리의 잘못된 관리 또는 무능력.
It's because of the global economic crisis.
때문이에요 글로벌 경제 위기.
Without immediate government intervention,
정부의 즉각적인 개입 없이는
the situation could end up becoming a runaway train.
상황은 끝날 수도 있다 폭주열차가 됩니다.
Just as banks and securities firms
은행이나 증권회사와 마찬가지로
provide people with loans when they need money,
사람들에게 대출을 제공하다 돈이 필요할 때,
the government should provide financial support now in the same vein.
정부가 제공해야 이제 같은 맥락에서 재정적 지원이 이루어집니다.
We've internally reviewed the opinions you shared earlier.
내부적으로 검토한 결과 이전에 공유한 의견입니다.
However, it'll be difficult
하지만, 힘들겠지
to provide public funds across the board.
전면적으로 공공 자금을 제공합니다.
To assess financial soundness,
재무건전성을 평가하기 위해서는
we will need a repayment plan proposal
상환 계획 제안이 필요합니다
and audited financial statements from the last three years.
그리고 감사받은 재무제표 지난 3년부터.
Submitting those financial statements will work against us in many ways.
재무제표 제출 여러 가지 방법으로 우리에게 불리하게 작용할 것입니다.
Then make it so that they work for us.
그런 다음 그들이 우리를 위해 일할 수 있도록 만드십시오.
Are you suggesting falsified accounting?
위조된 회계를 제안하는 겁니까?
It's not like the government can hand out money left and right.
정부가 할 수 있는 일이 아니다. 돈을 좌우로 나눠주세요.
We must go through the motions for the sake of appearances.
우리는 동작을 거쳐야합니다 외모를 위해서.
President Shin.
신 회장님.
It's just a formality,
그냥 형식적인 얘기인데,
so do your best to make the numbers add up nicely.
그러니 최선을 다해 숫자가 잘 합산됩니다.
Put that accounting experience to good use.
그 회계 경험을 담아 잘 활용하기 위해.
You should review
당신은 검토해야
and submit the final copy yourself.
최종 사본을 직접 제출하세요.
Yes, sir. I will.
네, 선생님. 그럴게요.
Ms. Song.
송 씨.
Put together a team for him.
그를 위해 팀을 구성하세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
I've called this meeting to make an announcement.
내가 이 회의를 소집했어 발표를 하려고.
Ms. Hong's probationary period is officially over.
홍씨의 수습기간 공식적으로 끝났습니다.
A round of applause.
박수를 보냅니다.
By the way…
그런데…
did Mr. Bang Jin-mok call out today?
오늘 방진목씨가 전화하셨나요?
I just heard he's going to be out for the next four days.
방금 그 사람이 나갈 거라고 들었어 앞으로 4일 동안.
Mr. Cha from Research and Mr. So from Trading are also away.
연구실 차씨 그리고 무역회사의 소씨도 자리를 비웠습니다.
So-Bang-Cha are all on vacation?
소방차는 모두 휴가 중인가요?
Something is fishy.
뭔가 수상해요.
I looked into it.
나는 그것을 조사했다.
Man, it turns out Chairman Kang, that sly old fox,
아, 그러고보니 강회장은, 저 교활한 늙은 여우,
asked the government for money with his head held high.
정부에 돈을 요구했다 머리를 높이 들고.
And the government is no better.
그리고 정부도 나을 것이 없습니다.
They agreed to release public funds
그들은 공공 자금을 공개하기로 합의했습니다.
to the companies that submit accounting records.
회사들에게 회계 기록을 제출하는 것입니다.
Good grief, what is this country coming to?
좋은 슬픔, 이 나라는 어떻게 되는 걸까?
They wouldn't do it out in the open since it's "confidential."
그들은 공개적으로 그런 짓을 하지 않을 거야 왜냐하면 "기밀"이기 때문입니다.
There are no conference rooms on the first floor,
회의실이 없습니다. 1층에는,
and the 12th floor only has executive offices.
그리고 12층 행정실만 있어요.
DESIGNATED PARKING
지정 주차
AREA CLOSED DO NOT USE
폐쇄된 지역 사용하지 마십시오
NOVEMBER 29, 1997 SATURDAY, 5:12 A.M.
1997년 11월 29일 토요일 오전 5시 12분
AUTHORIZED PERSONNEL ONLY
승인된 직원만 가능
How do I get in here?
여기에 어떻게 들어가나요?
You can't be here!
당신은 여기있을 수 없습니다!
Why not?
왜 안 돼?
Are you doing something I shouldn't see?
내가 봐서는 안되는 일을 하고 있는 거야?
I asked you for some time!
시간 좀 달라고 했어요!
We need to put out the immediate fire before we move on to…
즉시 불을 진압해야 합니다 다음으로 넘어가기 전에…
Ms. Hong.
홍 선생님.
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
Well, you see…
글쎄요…
Hello, sir.
안녕하세요, 선생님.
What are you doing here, Ms. Hong Jang-mi?
홍장미씨 여기서 뭐하세요?
Well…
음…
I came to see Mr. Bang.
방씨를 만나러 왔습니다.
Mr. Oh asked me to see if he needed help with anything.
오씨가 나보고 보자고 했어 그에게 도움이 필요한 것이 있다면.
I don't. Get lost.
나는 아니에요. 길을 잃다.
Wait.
기다리다.
We're on a tight schedule.
우리 일정이 빡빡해요.
Don't we need a clerical assistant for menial tasks
사무 보조원은 필요하지 않나요? 하찮은 일을 위해
like coffee runs, copies, and lunch delivery?
커피런처럼, 카피처럼 그리고 점심 배달은요?
-We do. -We don't.
- 그렇죠. - 우리는 그렇지 않습니다.
Ms. Hong may have a nasty temper and all…
홍씨는 성질이 급할 수도 있고...
but she's quick on her feet.
하지만 그녀는 발이 빠르다.
I am quick on my feet, and provide helpful assistance.
나는 발이 빠르다. 도움이 되는 도움을 제공하세요.
Please help out as much as you can.
최대한 도와주세요.
The president is here.
대통령이 여기 있습니다.
Including the president, we'll need…
대통령을 포함해서 우리는…
nine cups of coffee. Two sugars, two creams.
커피 아홉 잔. 설탕 2개, 크림 2개.
Yes, sir. I'll be right back.
네, 선생님. 곧 돌아올게요.
Oh, boy.
아, 얘야.
BREAK ROOM
휴게실
This isn't a coffee shop. You'll drink what I give you.
이곳은 커피숍이 아닙니다. 너는 내가 주는 것을 마실 것이다.
Cha Jung-il's grain powder mix.
차정일씨의 곡물가루 믹스.
Sneak a spoonful for three years of bad luck.
한숟가락 떠서 3년 동안의 불운을 위해.
Nice, a healthy snack.
좋아요, 건강한 간식이군요.
But why did Shin Jung-woo allow it?
그런데 신정우는 왜 허락했을까?
He knows what I'm up to.
그 사람은 내가 무엇을 하고 있는지 알고 있어요.
I'd better get back before Cha Jung-il flips out.
돌아가는 게 나을 것 같아 차정일이 뒤집히기 전에.
It's so damn good.
정말 좋아요.
That stingy man was saving it for himself.
그 인색한 사람이 자기를 위해 아껴두었던 것입니다.
-Good morning. -Hello.
-좋은 아침이에요. -안녕하세요.
What's this familiar yet uneasy situation that I don't hate?
익숙하면서도 불안한 이 상황은 뭘까 내가 싫어하지 않는다고?
I have joined the task force team with Mr. Bang.
태스크포스팀에 합류했어요 방씨와 함께.
You're not asking to go,
당신은 가자고 하는 것이 아닙니다.
but you already are?
그런데 넌 벌써 그래?
If that's President Shin,
그게 신 회장이라면,
please tell him that you asked me to help Mr. Bang--
그에게 말해주세요 당신이 나에게 방 씨를 도와달라고 요청했다는 것--
President Shin?
신 회장?
Yes, I've called to confirm something.
네, 확인하려고 전화했어요.
Did you ask Ms. Hong to assist Mr. Bang?
홍 선생님께 방 선생님을 도와달라고 부탁하셨나요?
Well…
음…
Yes, I did.
네, 그랬어요.
Thank you for confirming.
확인해 주셔서 감사합니다.
That's the least I can do for my savior.
그것이 나의 구원자를 위해 내가 할 수 있는 최소한의 일이다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I helped her out.
나는 그녀를 도왔습니다.
-Pardon? -What?
-뭐라고요? -무엇?
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
It's the final draft. Keep it safe.
최종안입니다. 안전하게 보관하세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
FINAL DRAFT FOR SUBMISSION
제출을 위한 최종 초안
I should empty this bin first.
먼저 이 통을 비워야 해요.
1996 FINANCIAL AUDIT REPORT
1996년 재무 감사 보고서
How dare they try to cook the books and steal taxpayers' money?
어떻게 감히 책을 요리하려고 합니까? 납세자의 돈을 훔치나요?
You'll submit the original records for fair and square evaluation.
원본 기록을 제출하게 됩니다. 공정하고 공정한 평가를 위해
Come in.
들어오세요.
Right.
그렇죠.
These are the materials prepared by the crisis response task force team.
에서 준비한 재료들입니다 위기대응TF팀.
We adjusted the sales figures to bring the company back into the black.
판매 수치를 조정했습니다 회사를 흑자로 되돌리기 위해.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
This is your specialty, after all.
결국 이것은 당신의 전문 분야입니다.
I'm sure you did well.
나는 당신이 잘했다고 확신합니다.
When is the submission deadline?
제출 마감일은 언제인가요?
It's 6 p.m. today.
오후 6시입니다. 오늘.
I see.
알겠어요.
Good work.
잘했어요.
Yes?
예?
I'll get the submission copy ready.
제출 사본을 준비하겠습니다.
Bang, grab me the printed submission copy and make a copy of the floppy disk.
쾅, 인쇄된 제출 사본 나한테 갖다줘 그리고 플로피 디스크의 복사본을 만드세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
-How many copies are you submitting? -Just one.
-몇 부를 제출하시나요? - 하나만요.
Are you taking it to the president?
그걸 대통령한테 가져가는 거야?
He's coming here to pick it up.
그 사람이 그것을 가지러 여기로 올 거예요.
No more questions! Just prepare the envelopes.
더 이상 질문이 없습니다! 봉투만 준비해주세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
FINANCIAL REPORT
재무 보고서
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
Stand up. Quicky!
일어서세요. 빨리!
THE DOCUMENTS PREPARED BY KEUM-BO
금보가 준비한 서류
It's all set to be submitted.
제출할 준비가 모두 완료되었습니다.
Thank you for your hard work.
여러분의 노고에 감사드립니다.
Not at all.
별말씀을요.
This is the final submission copy and the floppy disk.
최종 제출본입니다 그리고 플로피 디스크.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
-Let's go. -Yes, sir.
-갑시다. - 네, 선생님.
President Shin!
신회장님!
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
You should've been given the finalized copy, but you weren't.
너에게 주어졌어야 했어 최종본은 완성되었지만 당신은 그렇지 않았습니다.
This is…
이것은…
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
The one with the folded corner
모서리가 접힌 쪽
contains the original records that I prepared.
원본 기록이 포함되어 있습니다. 내가 준비한 것.
DETAILS OF OUTSTANDING LIABILITIES
미결제 부채의 세부 사항
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
The government has decided to inject public funds
정부는 다음과 같이 결정했다. 공적자금을 투입하다
to protect depositors and stabilize the markets…
예금자를 보호하기 위해 시장을 안정시키고…
Mom, I'm here.
엄마, 나 여기 있어요.
What?
무엇?
How come you're here on a weekday afternoon?
왜 여기에 왔어요? 평일 오후?
I worked through the night yesterday,
어제 밤새도록 일했는데,
so they gave me a day off as a special perk or something.
그래서 나한테 하루 휴가를 줬어 특별한 특전이라던가 그런 것 말이죠.
Mom, can you pack me some side dishes?
엄마, 반찬 좀 싸주시겠어요?
The family…
가족은…
I mean, my colleagues enjoy them so much.
내 말은, 내 동료들이 그걸 너무 좋아한다는 거야.
Of course, I'll pack you some.
물론, 내가 좀 싸줄게.
Where's Dad?
아빠는 어디 계시나요?
Is he at the market?
그 사람이 시장에 있어요?
He went to get a refund.
그는 환불을 받으러 갔다.
Business has been slow,
사업이 부진했고,
and your dad did something out of character.
그리고 네 아빠가 뭔가를 했어 성격이.
Apparently, he bought something called New Korea.
분명히 뭔가를 샀던 것 같은데 뉴코리아라고 부른다.
It's some kind of investment fund.
일종의 투자펀드죠.
A fund?
펀드?
The New Korea Fund?
뉴코리아펀드?
Yeah.
응.
But don't worry, I told him to sell all of it today.
하지만 걱정하지 마세요. 오늘 다 팔아버리라고 했어요.
Damn it.
젠장.
Why do you look like that?
왜 그렇게 보이나요?
Did you sell them off?
그것들을 팔았나요?
It's at minus 80%.
마이너스 80%에요.
What?
무엇?
Dad, why would you buy that?
아빠, 그걸 왜 사시겠어요?
You're the one who told Jang-mi and me that stocks ruin lives.
장미랑 나한테 말한 건 너야 주식이 인생을 망치는군요.
They're not stocks.
그것들은 주식이 아닙니다.
I bought it because it was a fund.
펀드라서 샀어요.
I asked them for a refund, and they said it's impossible.
환불해달라고 했는데, 그리고 그들은 그것이 불가능하다고 말했습니다.
But Hanmin is the top-ranked company in the country.
그런데 한민이는 국내 1위 기업.
What are we going to do?
우리는 무엇을 할 것인가?
How could they do this?
그들은 어떻게 이런 일을 할 수 있었습니까?
Honey, what are we going to do?
여보, 우리 뭘 할 거예요?
Damn it…
젠장…
It's down 90%!
90% 하락했어요!
You sold me the fund!
나한테 펀드를 팔았잖아!
What are you going to do about my hard-earned money?
당신은 무엇을 할 예정입니까? 내가 힘들게 번 돈에 대해?
I'm really sorry, ma'am.
정말 죄송해요, 부인.
Let me cancel the automatic transfer first.
취소하겠습니다 먼저 자동 이체를 해보세요.
The branch manager said the head office is working on a resolution.
지점장님이 본사라고 하더군요. 결의안을 마련 중입니다.
Hey, we'll be screwed if Hanmin goes under!
야, 우리 망할 거야 한민이 망하면!
You'll pay for this.
당신은 이것에 대한 비용을 지불합니다.
I will sue you!
나는 당신을 고소할 것이다!
Answer me!
대답해주세요!
-What are you going to do about this? -Please don't do this!
-이 일을 어떻게 할 건가요? - 제발 이러지 마세요!
BRANCH MANAGER'S OFFICE
지점장실
Sir!
선생님!
-Sir! -Hey!
-선생님! -여기요!
-Please help me! -Give me back my money!
-도와주세요! -내 돈 돌려줘!
Please try to calm down.
진정해 보세요.
What are you going to do?
당신은 무엇을 할 예정입니까?
I'm so sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
INTERNATIONAL INTEREST RATES, STOCK PRICES
국제 금리, 주가
Doesn't this seem embellished?
이건 장식된 것 같지 않나요?
Are these numbers even possible?
이 숫자가 가능할까요?
Yeongsan Investment & Securities is out.
영산투자증권이 나왔습니다.
All right, next.
알았어, 다음.
We're moving on to Hanmin Investment & Securities.
우리는 계속 나아가고 있어요 한민투자증권으로.
-Okay. -While you review the file,
-좋아요. -파일을 검토하는 동안,
you must review if they'll be able to repay the funds.
당신은 검토해야합니다 자금을 상환할 수 있는지 여부.
That should be our focus.
그것이 우리의 초점이 되어야 합니다.
-Yes, sir.
- 네, 선생님.
SECURITIES
증권
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
didn't make the cut?
잘리지 않았어?
Why is our name missing from that roster?
그 명단에서 왜 우리 이름이 빠졌나요?
Why?
왜?
I've never experienced such humiliation in my life!
나는 한번도 경험해본 적이 없다. 내 인생에서 이런 굴욕이라니!
All we did was
우리가 한 일은
do those other firms a goddamn favor!
다른 회사들에게 빌어먹을 부탁을 해라!
-I'm sorry, sir.
-죄송합니다, 선생님.
Unbelievable!
믿을 수 없는!
Goddamn it!
젠장!
I'm certain
나는 확신한다
I personally handed off the documents I prepared.
개인적으로 양보했어요 내가 준비한 서류.
That day,
그날,
Ms. Hong Jang-mi followed me to the parking lot.
홍장미 선생님이 저를 따라오셨어요 주차장으로.
You know her, right?
그 사람 알지?
Ms. Hong did?
홍씨가 그랬어요?
She said I took the wrong envelope,
내가 봉투를 잘못 가져갔다고 하더군요.
and gave me another one.
그리고 나에게 또 하나를 주었다.
Weren't those documents also prepared by you, Mr. Bang?
그 서류 아니었나요? 방 선생님께서 준비하신 것도 있나요?
Thank you for your hard work.
여러분의 노고에 감사드립니다.
Not at all.
별말씀을요.
This is…
이것은…
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
DETAILS OF OUTSTANDING LIABILITIES
미결제 부채의 세부 사항
JULY, 1997 HONG KONG
1997년 7월 홍콩
The financial crisis that began in Thailand spread to Indonesia.
시작된 금융위기 태국에서 인도네시아로 퍼졌습니다.
Where will it strike next?
다음에는 어디를 칠 것인가?
Korea is next.
그 다음은 한국이다.
So process my resignation immediately.
그러니 즉시 사직을 처리해 주십시오.
You're anticipating Korea's financial crisis,
당신은 기대하고 있습니다 한국의 금융위기,
yet you'll become the president of Hanmin?
그런데 당신이 한민의 사장이 될 겁니까?
Securities firms have the fastest, most credible intel on Korean companies.
증권사가 가장 빠르고, 한국 기업에 대한 가장 신뢰할 수 있는 정보입니다.
When the executives start floundering,
경영진이 허둥대기 시작하면,
I'll make a clean sweep.
깨끗하게 청소하겠습니다.
Everyone has such aspirations at times.
누구나 그런 소망을 가질 때가 있습니다.
Mine's not an aspiration.
내 것은 열망이 아닙니다.
I'm solving a problem I already know the answer to.
문제를 해결하고 있어요 나는 이미 그 답을 알고 있다.
PUBLIC FUND INJECTION INTO FINANCIAL SECTOR
공적자금 투입 금융 부문으로
HANMIN EXCLUDED
한민 제외
That was your doing.
그건 당신이 한 일이에요.
If we go bankrupt,
우리가 파산하면,
thousands of employees will be out on the streets.
수천 명의 직원 거리로 나올 것입니다.
Is that the justice you seek?
그게 당신이 추구하는 정의인가요?
Then should I have just let you cook books and loot public funds?
그럼 그냥 널 그냥 두었어야 했는데? 책을 요리하고 공공 자금을 약탈합니까?
Chairman Kang exploits crises to line his own pockets.
강 회장은 위기를 이용한다 자신의 주머니에 줄을 서기 위해.
Would you stay complicit while his employees, investors,
계속 공모하시겠습니까? 그의 직원, 투자자,
and the public pay the price for his corruption?
그리고 대중 그의 부패에 대한 대가를 치르겠습니까?
I just did what I had to do.
나는 단지 내가 해야 할 일을 했을 뿐입니다.
I was trying to save my colleagues,
동료들을 구하려고 했는데,
not to blow the company to pieces!
회사를 산산조각 내지 않으려면!
Are you using your colleagues to justify yourself?
동료를 이용하고 있는가? 자신을 정당화하려고?
Right. I almost forgot.
오른쪽. 나는 거의 잊었다.
You're so devoted that you even led the accounting fraud nine years ago.
당신은 지도할 정도로 헌신적이에요 9년 전 분식회계.
We've met before.
우리는 전에 만난 적이 있어요.
Please take good care of us.
우리를 잘 보살펴 주세요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Sorry, Keum-bo.
미안해요, 금보 씨.
I'll persuade him to do the right thing.
나는 그가 옳은 일을 하도록 설득할 것이다.
…committed suicide by jumping from his apartment building
… 뛰어내려 자살했다 그의 아파트 건물에서
around 3 p.m. today.
오후 3시쯤 오늘.
The Hanmin accounting fraud case in 1988.
1988년 한민 분식회계 사건.
Do you remember the accountant who jumped to his death back then?
회계사를 기억하시나요? 그때 뛰어내려 죽은 사람은 누구였나요?
He was my mentor.
그는 나의 멘토였습니다.
He was my colleague.
그는 내 동료였습니다.
I guess that settles it.
그걸로 해결될 것 같아요.
Even in the thick of the storm…
짙은 폭풍 속에서도…
we'll never be in the same boat.
우리는 결코 같은 배에 타지 않을 것입니다.
Never.
절대.
UNDERCOVER MISS HONG
언더커버 미스홍
All signs point to us ending the operation.
모든 징후는 우리를 가리킨다 작전을 종료합니다.
Let's wrap it up.
마무리합시다.
But I wasn't trying to hide it.
하지만 숨기려고 한 건 아니었어요.
You never asked who my dad was.
당신은 우리 아버지가 누구인지 묻지 않았습니다.
If you think about it, you're the biggest liar here.
당신이 그것에 대해 생각한다면, 당신은 여기서 가장 큰 거짓말쟁이입니다.
Damn it!
젠장!
You damn brat!
빌어먹을 놈아!
I'm D.K. Lee of DK Ventures.
저는 D.K입니다. DK벤처스 이사장.
If Hanmin goes bankrupt on its own? That's a win for me.
한민이 스스로 파산한다면? 그것은 나에게 승리입니다.
A 40% staff reduction?
직원 40% 감축?
Show respect to your senior.
선배에게 존경심을 표현하세요.
Senior?
상위?
Director Yun, I found it.
윤 감독님, 찾았어요.
The slush fund ledger.
비자금 장부입니다.
Subtitle translation by: Justin S. Kim
자막 번역: Justin S. Kim